Guide to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Photograph Collection ALBA.PHOTO.015
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- Series I: Photographs, 1930s-1990s.
  - Subseries I:A: Individuals
    - Pollack, Samuel Emil, undated (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Post, Langdon W., undated (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Prago, Albert, Aug 23, 1990, undated (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Prince, Clarence Isom (in pajamas), undated (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Provenzano, Mercurio [aka Mike], undated (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Pulkkinen, George Albert, undated (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Pylkki, Ragnar, undated (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Quinones, Gabriel Jack, undated (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - Raddock, Mike (Spain), undated (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Ragawskas, Albin, undated (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - Rappaport, Irving, undated (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - Rautbart, Anthony (fox hole), undated (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Raven, Robert J., undated (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - Reed, Robert Lee, undated (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - Reed, William Allen, undated (Box 2, Folder 109)
    - Rehil, Joseph Francis (1938), undated (Box 2, Folder 110)
    - Reiter, Peter, undated (Box 2, Folder 111)
    - Reitz, John, undated (Box 2, Folder 112)
    - Richards, Frank (portrait); (at podium), undated (Box 2, Folder 113)
    - Ripps, Alfred (with unidentified woman), undated (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - Roach, Douglas Bryan (parading at First National VALB Conference); (shirtless, arms folded), Feb 12, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - Robertson, Milton, undated (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Robeson, Paul (speaking at VALB 5th National Convention, with General Karol Swierczewski); (with I. B. staff, "near Albacete"), Sep 21, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - Robinson, Edward, undated (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - Rogers, Frank, undated (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Rolfe, Edwin (sitting on truck); (standing), undated (Box 2, Folder 120)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano (charcoal drawing), undated (Box 2, Folder 121)
    - Roosevelt, Patrick (portrait); (standing, 2 photos); (seated, exposing artificial leg); (seated, with cane), undated (Box 2, Folder 122)
    - Rosenstein, Joe (playing ping-pong), undated (Box 2, Folder 123)
    - Rossen, John, undated (Box 2, Folder 124)
    - Rowen, John, undated (Box 2, Folder 125)
    - Rowlson, Lester, undated (Box 2, Folder 126)
    - Rubin, Henry, undated (Box 2, Folder 127)
    - Sands, Joseph, undated (Box 2, Folder 128)
    - Sanford, Albert B., undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Schneiderman, Rubin [aka Ruby], undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Schofs, Fred Jacob, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Schrenzel, Isadore (photo-postcard, and original photo), Jul 1937 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Schuler, Maynard, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Schultman Walter J., undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Schultz, Elias (posing with Army officers); (Receiving medal), undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Seacord, Douglas Earl, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Secundy, Louis, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Segovias, Antonio (Sergeant, Lincoln-Washington Battalion, Spain), undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Service, Elman Rogers, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Shafran, Jack, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Shapiro, Arthur (3 photos), ca. 1936-1939 1992 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Shapiro, Saul Meyer, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Shiff, Solomon, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Shimbari, Giovanni, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Shipler, Reverend Guy Emery, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Shipman, Evan, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Shirai, Jack (photo postcard of group of soldiers, Madrid), 1937 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Shugrue, Dan (in Spain), undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Simon, John, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Singer, Bernie (negative only), undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Skolnick, Abraham (portrait, with biographical information), undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Small, John, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Smercka, Radomir, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Smith, Ferdinand C. (at podium), undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Smith, Harold (at reunion), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Smith, Harold L., undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Smorodin, Abe (VALB Nicaragua trip, with Flor Cerrano, of Spanish Communist Party), 1989 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Snyder, John W., undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Soong, Ching-Ling (Madame Sun Yat-Sen), undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Soule Echevaria, Carlos (political prisoner, "mug shot," Spain), undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Sovietsky, Bunni (2 photos), undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Spiller, Samuel, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Stamiatakos, Nick, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Steel, Johannes (commentator for WMCA Radio), undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Stefanovic, V. P., Nov 24, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Stember, Sam, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Stone, Al [aka Al Gottlieb], undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Stone, Harold, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Stone, Hy [aka Herman Hersh; Hershkowitz], undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Stout, Frank, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Strauss, Walter Frederick (bicycle), undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Sturgeon, Peter A., undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Svorinich, John S., undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Swan, William G. [aka Ryan], undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Swierczewski, General Karol [aka "General Walter"] (portrait, 2 photos); (inspecting partisan troops); (rifle range; 2 photos); ("surrounded by a bevy of beauties"), undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Tanttila, Reino Herman ("Ray Tantila the bravest comrade I knew," Madrid), Nov 12, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Taylor, Daniel Bede, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Teiger, Jacob, undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Thayer, Donald, undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Thomas, Steve, undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Thomson, Godfrey Edward, undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Thornton, Nathan James, undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Thorpe, Guy, undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Titleman, Nathan, undated (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Todorovich, Alex (in group of soldiers in train car), undated (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Topolianos, Steve, undated (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Traka, John (2 photos), undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Truy, Joseph D., undated (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Van Arsdale, Alvin (Helen Keller and Robert Raven visit AV at the Hospital for Joint Diseases), Oct 1938 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Vaughn, Joseph, undated (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Voros, Sandor, undated (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Wadman, Bror, undated (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Waitzman, Samuel, undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Walter, [Nicholai?] (and Modesto, at Quinto), 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Washuk, Mike, undated (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Weinberg, Jerry, undated (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Weisenfeld, Nathan, undated (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Weissman, Oscar (with Ernest Hemingway), undated (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Welles, Orson (with two women), undated (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Wellman, Saul, undated (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Wendorf, Larry, undated (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Wendorf, Paul (group, MacKenzie Papineau Battalion Company 5, [Oct 12, 1936]); (portrait, Dec 1937); (reading newspaper in group, [Oct 12, 1936]); (Vera's house, Oct 12, 1936), 1936-1937 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Wheeler, William (undated); (1935, organizing Teamsters) (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - White, David McKelvy, undated (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - White, Milton [aka Morris], undated (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Whittier, Mark, undated (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Widder, Louis, undated (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Wildergans, Gustave [aka Gus], undated (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Wildman, Earl, undated (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Wileman, Henry, undated (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Willet, Sam (MacKenzie Papineau Battalion after Belchite Campaign in Almochuel), undated (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Williams, John, undated (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Wimmer, William, undated (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Wirta, Paul, undated (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Wisen, Erik (and wife giving presents to children, Spain), undated (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Wolff, Milton: (portrait); (at front, anti-Fascism picket on Madison Ave, Feb or Mar 1947, 2 photos); (with pipe, New York Committee to Win the Peace Picket, Betty Gannett also pictured, 1946; 2 photos); (at podium, VALB 5th National Convention, Sep 21, 1946); (speaking at Free Spain Rally, 3 photos); (at event, [1940s?]), undated (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Wolman, Eugene, undated (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Yanowsky, Harry, undated (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Yates, James, undated (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Yick, Dong Hong (negative only), undated (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Zamares, Joe [aka Zameres], undated (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Zecevich, Milan, undated (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Ziedman, Frank, undated (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Zivin, Louis, undated (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Zoule, George, undated (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Zowadowski, Joseph, undated (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Subseries I:B: Individuals in Groups
    - Aalto, William and Irving Goff (in front of VALB flag), ca.1936-1939 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Ades, Bernard and Abel Plenn, [1940s] (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Allen, George; Alfred Goertz, M. Krauthamer (died in Spain, memorial service), ca.1936-1939 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Altman, David and Benjamin Goldring (Mataro Hospital), 1938 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Amlie, Hans; Ralph Bates, and unidentified men [Spain?], ca.1936-1939, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Arnitz, Louis; Richard Browne, Maurice Conway, Raymond Massey, and David White (backstage Party, "Abe Lincoln in Illinois") (Arnitz with Massey), [Oct 15, 1938], [Dec 1939] (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Barris, Bill; Joe Drill, Dick Fein, Milton Felson, Alex Nichta, Pat Roosevelt, Harold Smith, and General Walters ([after Spain]), undated (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - Barsky, Dr. Edward K. and Dr. Jose Giral (publicity photo and text for Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee, [after 1944]), undated (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Begelman, Elias, Hy Stone, Joe Stone, Sam Stone, and Jerry Weinberg (Spain), ca.1936-1939 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Berg, Nils; Aaron Harris, Len Levenson Al Prago, and Harold Smith (drinking; collection plate in front of counter), ca.1936-1939 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Bradley, Captain Lou; Frances Farmer and Carl Spender (at a party), ca.1937-1946 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Bridenthal, Kenneth; Philip Crane, Joseph Sands and Dr. Simon (at a party), ca.1937-1946 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Canete, Antonio; Luis Edo; Alfredo Herrera; Alicia Mur, and Jesus Rodriguez (photo leaflet, "Federacion Iberica de Juventudes Libertarias"), [1940s] (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Carsman, Sam; Henry Eisman; Dolores Ibarruri and Saul Wellman (with bust of Lenin, Moscow), Jan 1969 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Chase, Allan; Jo Davidson and Vincent Sheehan (seated at table), ca.1936-1946 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Chi, Chang; Ching Sin Ling and Wa Fon Liu ("Chinese Comrades"), 1938 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Chisholm, Albert and George Waters (ambulance drivers), ca.1936-1939 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Churchill, Winston; Franklin Delano Roosevelt and Joseph Stalin (Tehran, 1943) (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Clarke, David; Will Greer, and Bill Wheeler (sign petition to lift the embargo), undated (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Cooper, Jack; Narciso Gonzalez and Rafael Maltes (Spain Special Machine Gun Company), ca.1936-1939 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Copic, Vladimir and Mirko Markovich ("Commander Wash.") (in Spain), ca.1936-1939 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - Dart, Roland; Edwin Rolfe; Milton Wolff and unidentified men (in Spain), ca.1936-1939 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Dimitrof, Jorge and Dolores Ibarruri ("Spanish Civil War Photographic Collage" with posters, and a VALB parade), undated (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Doran, David; Marion Merriman and Robert Merriman (in Spain), ca.1936-1939 (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Dunbar, Malcolm; Cecil Smith, and Milton Wolff (with large group of soldiers), 1936-1939 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Estrella, Miguel and Helen Padua (rehabilitation director interviews veteran, possibly published in Doctor and Patient), [1938] (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Feldman, Sol and Herman Ungar (in Spain), ca.1936-1939 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Finnick, Gene and Arthur Shapiro ("Aviator") (pose with Mrs. Freed, the mother of prisoner Ed Freed), ca.1936-1938 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Flaherty, Charles; Edward Flaherty, Frank Flaherty and William J. Flaherty (their father) (in front of maps of Spain, includes text, 2 photos), [1938] (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Franco, Francisco and Adolf Hitler (shaking hands), ca.1936-1938 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Franco, Francisco and Benito Mussolini, ca.1936-1945 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Frazer, Hamish; Dr. Hene and Major Smith, ca.1936-1939 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Galleani, Humberto; Ernest Hemingway; Robert Merriman; Louis Secundy ("head of transport autopool") and unidentified soldiers (in Spain), ca.1937-1939 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Gibbon, Joseph; Ed Pierson, and unidentified man, undated (Box 3, Folder 131a)
    - Halowell, Bill; Nick Hanzuck (Toronto), Pete Shimrack, Stewart [? - Vancouver], and many unidentified soldiers (Canadian Volunteers in Lincoln Brigade "and 2 guests then in the ALB of 15th International Brigade," posed with dog, Albares), Mar 1937 (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Harvey, William and Hy Rossman (injured), [1937-1938] (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Jackson, Burt; Robert Raven; General Karl Swierczewski (with six unidentified men), undated (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Katine, Ben; "Dave", undated (Box 3, Folder 134a)
    - Keller, Fred and Milton Wolff (pack boxes addressed "To the Red Army" in front of ALB Banner), [1940]-[1942] (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Klein, Herman [aka Gabby]; "Doc" [Joseph] Roffman and Moish Tobman, [1942]-[1945] (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Lamb, Little, Lustgarten, North, O'Flaherty, Rolfe, Ruscitans, Tabb, Taylor, Watt, and unidentified soliders, undated (Box 3, Folder 136a)
    - Lenthier, Kate and David McKelvy White [Chairman of FALB] (Kate Lenthier was the "wife of John Lenthier, actor, killed in action at Jarama" and McKelvy's secretary), Feb 1937 (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Lustgarten, Larry; Richard Rusciano; Donald Thayer; Emmanuel Lausser; Milton Wolff; George Watt; Harold Smith; Archie Brown (Officers of Lincoln Battalion in Spain "after the last battle"), Sep 1938 (Box 3, Folder 137a)
    - Longo, Luigi; Malojee "Edward" Bolestraw, and Andre Marty (among large group of soldiers standing in formation), ca.1936-1939 (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - Marquette, Edward M.; Dave A. Miller and John Rossen (in WWII uniform), [1942-1945] (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Prago, Albert and Tauno Sundsten (with explanatory letter), 1937 (Box 3, Folder 139a)
    - Robinson, Edward "Frenchy" and Joseph Albert Whalen (in Spain), ca.1936-1938 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - White, David McKelvy and Hy Rossman (talking, Rossman injured), [1937-1938] (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Subseries I:C: Subjects, General
    - Ambete: Elias Begelman and Vladimir Copic and unidentified soldiers, Nov 1937 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Ambulances and Mobile Operating Rooms (9 photos), ca.1936-1938 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Aragon Retreat: "Observers, Aragon Retreat, Marcelina Marot and Letux Harvey Hall" (duplicate? see ALBA Photo 11), Mar 1938 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Barcelona: ("Before the Procession," "Batallon Palafox, Batallon Vaillant Couturier, Nino Nannetti Sallud, Batallon Andre Marti"); (bombed buildings); (dome, Oct 1938); (parade leaving, Oct 1938, 7 photos), undated, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Battalion 59 (Co. 1, Melchor Pajon and Antonio Sanchez); Battalion 59, (Co. 2: Pedro Aguila Rio,; Ten. Geronimo Lopez, Luis Peraza, Spain, standing in field); Battalion 59, (Machine Gun Co., Pedro Jofre, Francisco Media Aldea; Felipe Perez; Ricardo Rodrigo; Antonio Sanchez; Diego Segura and Antonio Valera, Spain), ca.1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Belchite: Architecture before and after Battle of Belchite, 18 photos total (includes pages of pamphlet of 15th Brigade; Ayuntamiento: One of the Last Fascist Strongholds), ca.Aug 1937-Sep 1937, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Belchite: (general); (camping in Almuchuel after Belchite); (officer prisoners); (prisoners marching, postcard); (torn Fascist posters on wall), ca.Aug 1937-Sep 1937 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Benicasim, Fiesta Celebrating the Republic (French Volunteer in clown make-up); (children on shore); (race on shore, 4 photos), Jun 18, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Botwin Brigade [three men at a VALB function], ca.1980s-1990s (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Brigade Chorus, Jan 19, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - British Battalion: (Bill Alexander, Dave Doran, and Jim Ruskin, Spain, drilling); (Company 1, Charles James Framp, Juan Carrasco Navarro and James Pollock); (Company 2, Archie Cook, John Fanner, John Longstaff, Charles Nelson, Francisco Olmos, Juan Ponce; Johnny Power and Andrew Shaw posing in a field); (Machine Gun Company, Jesus Cano Candel, John Lobben, and Joaquim Plaza Videl); (Machine Gun Instruction); (Thirty-fifth Division), ca.1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Brunete (Fascist planes bombing road, clipping); (Steve Nelson; Douglas Roach, and two unidentified men); (water truck), [Jul, 6 1937-July, 25 1937] (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Caspanes before Ebro, Jul 1938 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Caspe: March through the Hills to Caspe, Mar 1938 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Casualties: Body in Road, ca.1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Casualties: Children (16 photos), ca.1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Children (with Battalion Louise Michel sign); (dining hall at a "Rural Residence" for Children, postcard); (residence at Denia); (girl distributes Communist literature); (with "Battalion 6 Fevrier" sign), ca.1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Cigarettes for Spain Campaign (FALB mass rally, Hippodrome): Lillian Morris Bossman; Rose Norman; Ruth Smith, and Mrs. William (3 photos), Sep 1, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Combat (soldiers firing rifles); (loading artillery); (soldier firing machine gun); (soldier with machine gun); (["Tank advancing towards the enemy lines"]; (wounded soldier ushered to rear, 1938), ca.1936-1937, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Combat behind Sandbags and in Trenches (7 photos), ca.1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Commissars: Antonio Gil Cabeza (Spanish Battalion); Bob Cooney (British Battalion); Frank Rogers (MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion); Jose Maria Varela (Adjutant Brigade Commissar); Sandor Voros (Head of Brigade Commissariat) and George Watt (Lincoln-Washington Battalion), Apr 22, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Coney Island, airplane banner to free prisoners, Jul 4, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 21a)
    - Dimitrov Battalion: Wall Newspaper, ca.1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Ebro, ("Crossing the Ebro": Maury Colow [Commissar MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion], "Hans" translator for Mac-Pap's, and unidentified); (Typed Spanish caption, "Group taken prisoner by Republican Army" ); (Typed Spanish caption, "Heads of Fascist army taken prisoner by Republican Army"); (Typed Spanish caption, "Republican leaders question a Fascist prisoner" 2 photos); (Typed Spanish caption, "Republican troops prepare for Ebro offensive"); (Republican camp); (Crossing Ebro, 5 photos, 1 via negative only), ca.1936-1939, [1938] (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Eighty-sixth Brigade: Trankler Fritz ("mit Brille"); Malina Leopold, Arnold Lustiger, and August Schuber ("St. Veit/Glan"), and unidentified man (" Sommer 1937 Sudfront 86. Brigade," Austrian volunteers, 2 different photos), ca.1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Farmers and Soldiers Raise Arms (large format), ca.1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - First Regiment: William Sennett and Group (may include Ralph Fasanella and Simon Morris Jokoffsky), ca.1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Fourteenth International Anti-Aircraft Battery: German Volunteers, ca.1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Graffito by Edward Muscala, Dec 1937, Chapel of Sant Gregorio, Aguaviva (includes explanatory correspondence), 2010 (Box 4, Folder 27a)
    - Guadalajara (Junked Truck on Road); (Refugees Board Truck), [Mar 1937] (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Gusti Jirku camp site, ca.1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - International Brigades (Battalion 59, Company 3: Sebastian Berdeguer, Antonio Garcia Martinez, Manuel Martin, Rafael Martinez Gil, Francisco Ortola, and Boleslaw Taichman, Spain); ( Fifteenth British Battalion Banner during visit with British students); (group in trench); (Wilton Epstein and Saul Wellman (sit on ambulance bumper); (troops marching, May 1938); (3 soldiers in the snow giving clenched fist salute, Jan 1938); (groups in town, small photo); (Mrs. Haldane); (keeping watch); ([Mail call?] in the field); (making maps); (amidst trees); (with motorcycles); (small photo, IB in a field); (with sandbags); (in trench, officers); (troops on truck, "oste ettre central" sign); (two men in "Dugout Home"); (wall newspaper, Sanidad Post), ca.1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - International Brigades, Combat, ca.1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - International Brigades, Posed Groups, ca.1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - International Brigades, Relaxation: (chess); (band concert); (jug band); (at campsite); (by roadside); (watching young ladies sewing); (writing a letter), ca.1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Iwo Jima: "Marines Capture Iwo Jima" (on back: Official U.S. Marine Corps Photo), Feb 2, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Jarama: General, [Feb 6, 1937]-[Feb, 27 1937] (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Krepp, Siegfried: Detail of Raised Stone, Berlin (postcard), undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Lincoln Battalion: (bulletin board); (eating and drinking outside tent); (Tom Mooney Machine Gun Company, 2 photos), ca.1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Lincoln Battalion: (Trifon P. Buzeff, Walter Gregory, and Charles Nusser (Madrid), Jul 16, 1937); (Durango, Sightseeing in a bombed out church); (formation prior to demobilization); ("Join Spanish people for dance behind the lines"); (wall newspaper, Comisariado ! No Pasaran! [poor photocopy]), Jul 16, 1937, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Lincoln Battalion: Soccer Game, ca.1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Lincoln Penny for a Lincoln Vet: (FALB rehabilitation campaign, 4 photos, mostly women, including Rosalind Carter and Jean Crystal); (Robert Raven, Thomas Ray, Joseph Earl Vaughn, Jerry Warren, Arnold Weinman, and David McKelvy White), ca. [1938] (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Lincoln-Washington Battalion: (Max Bowers and Guy Thorpe, Spain); (Company 1: Julian Andres, Francisco Morales, Miguel San Martin, and Victor Serinana, seated and smiling in field [Spain]); (Company 2, Marca: "Light Machine Gun," Jul 1938, poor photocopy); (Corbera, Jul 1938); (Darmos, after April 2, 1938 retreat); (May Day wall newspaper, 1938, Darmos, 2 unidentified International Brigade men); (Jarama, Firing in Trench, [Feb 6-27, 1937]); (speech, [Feb 6-27, 1937]); (standing in trench, [Feb 6-27, 1937]); (wall newspaper, [Feb 6-27, 1937]); (Teruel, marching to "North Pole," [Feb 6-27, 1937] poor photocopy); (trench at "North Pole"); (Co. 2, Bat. 59: Pedro Aguila Rio, Ten Geronimo Lopez, and Luis Peraza), ca.1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion (Carlos Arias, Roberto Asuncion, Renato Blanco, Julian DiDent, Miguel Donate, Gonzalo Encabo, Frank Goeginger, Tony Gomez, Antonio Orti, Vincente Parres, Jose Rodriguez, Al Stone, and Hans [unknown], Spain); (Co. Five, Jose Asensi, Deszo Beke, Yuhve Lehto, and Toivo Suni); (Ebro, four men in trench eating and smoking, [May 1938] 3 photos); (Ebro, rifleman in trenches, May 1938);: (parade); (groups); (Seguro de Bano action in trenches, Feb 1938); (Spanish cooks of Letur, Mar 1938); (Teruel: four soldiers, trench, Jan 1938); (Teruel: reading under cover, Jan 1938); (Tivissa: fiesta with civilians); (playing checkers, Spain, [Jul-Aug 1938]), ca.1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 42)